{
    "id": "f806de23f6584ce695e3bf27c222d986",
    "title": "Gap Fills Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "………………………. he wasn’t schooled, his common sense guided him through life.",
            "description": "We use though to connect two contrasting ideas.",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "Despite",
                "Though"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If he were more communicative, we ……………………………… know his true feelings.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "would have"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… he got a raise, he has been too complacent to work hard.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Since",
                "Ever since",
                "When"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The tenants complained that there ……………………….. not enough hot water.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, the verb in the subordinate clause too will be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The boy remained in concealment ……………………………. the bully went away.",
            "description": "Until refers to time up to refers to distance. ",
            "answers": [
                "until",
                "up to",
                "as far as"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Diplomas were conferred ……………………… members of the graduating class.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "with",
                "at",
                "on"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He would be a good pianist if he ………………………….. more confidence.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "had",
                "had had"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If a pregnant woman ………………………………. not take care of herself, she can give her baby congenital defects.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will / can + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "do",
                "does",
                "has"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "A conscientious worker arrives on time and ……………………… no mess behind him.",
            "description": "Parallel structure",
            "answers": [
                "leaving",
                "leaves",
                "left"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The world will run out of oil ………………………… it practices conservation.",
            "description": "Unless is similar to if.",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "until",
                "unless"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Those ………………………….. planned the rebellion were indicted for conspiracy against the king.",
            "description": "We use who to refer to people. Whom is used when the relative pronoun is the object of the relative clause.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "which",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Is that container ……………………………. to hold all the books?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "enough large",
                "large enough",
                "too large"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}